This video is a short introduction to containerization with Docker.
.
A container includes an application
and its dependencies.
Like a real world shipping container,
think of containers as
easy to ship and handle.
Docker is a particular containerization
technology. Inside a container you include
the code of your application and all runtime
libraries for the dependencies, in addition
to the system tools
and the configuration files.
The result is that the containerized
application will run identically
on any host without any incompatibility.
Traditionally, an operating system like
Ubuntu has a package manager that installs apps,
and the runtime
libraries shared among apps.
Therefore, applications are coupled, because
they have to share the same dependencies.
Using containerization, each application comes with its
libraries. Each application is isolated.
Now you can update each
application independently.
Containerization is different than using
virtual machines. In a
virtual machine deployment,
you have a host system that runs
a hypervisor like VMware.
The hypervisor divides the physical
hardware resources among the virtual machines.
Each virtual machine runs
its own operating system.
The disadvantage of this is that there is
considerable override and processes cannot
communicate over different
virtual machines.
Instead, containerization has minimal overhead
and it allows us to deploy multiple
applications so that they can
communicate with each other.
It's now common to deploy Web applications
using stacks of containers,
for example, you can deploy your blog
using a stack that contains
your own instance of a database and
your own instance of a Web server.
I want to give you
an overview of the Docker workflow.
There are two main commands,
"docker build" and "docker run". "Docker build"
builds an image from a Dockerfile.
Docker run creates a container
from the image and runs it.
In the following slides,
I will explain all of these terms.
You would run "docker build" in a directory
that contains the application code
and the Dockerfile. The Dockerfile
is the recipe for building the image.
An image is an archive with the packaged application.
Given an image, using "docker run",
we can produce many running containers.
I want to show you a minimal example.
You might have a directory
with a Python script called Hello.py.
This is a simple Dockerfile that creates
an image that packages the script.
In another video, we will see the meaning
of all commmands.
For now, notice that there this is a comment
"FROM" that specifies the base image.
The command "RUN" is used to call
the package manager and install
the dependencies. You can pin
the exact dependencies that you need.
The command "COPY" copies the script
inside the image. "CMD" makes
it the default executable.
Docket has a rich ecosystem of tools
for running and monitoring containers. Portainer is one such example.
It's  an interface that tells you which containers are running on your system.
Here we see what containers are running on a Duckiebot.
A Docker registry is an online service
that contains a database of Docker
images that anybody can use.
It's also possible to run
your own registry.
You can think of a Docker registry as
an app store that contains applications
you can install on your computer.
The largest registry is Dockerhub,
which we are going to use.
Often we will tell you to use a specific
image published on the Duckietown account.
If you're curious, you can go
and browse all available images.
I will show you how we can
share images using registries.
There are two different workflows, one
for the developer and one for the user.
A developer uses the command "docker build"
to build an image on their computer.
The command "Docker push"
uploads a copy to registry.
The user runs the comment "docker pulll"
to copy an image on their computer,
then "docker run" creates running
containers from the image.
Docker made developers life much easier.
Dockerfiles are a way to make builds
producible and documented.
With Docker, you have complete control
of your execution environment and you will
not have any incompatibility. Yet,
applications can communicate.
Finally, you have complete
control of the resource usage.
There are ways to limit the CPU
and RAM that a  container can use.
It's also possible to limit network
utilization, which increases security.