In the previous videos, I introduced the concept of autonomous vehicles
and the "levels of autonomy" classification.
In this video, I will tell you about the history of the field,
and how the vision for the use cases has evolved
during the years, and some economic considerations.
The study of autonomous vehicles in the sense of cars is relatively recent.
The earliest example was from 1986, when a German researcher, Professor
Dickmanns, demonstrated highway driving based on vision.
His experiments demonstrated that real-time control of heavy vehicles
was possible.
However, it was difficult to engineer reliable solutions because
of the technology available at the time.
The turning point for the field came around 2003.
A catalyst was a series of Grand Challenges created
by DARPA, The Advanced Research Projects Agency of the US military,
between 2004 and 2007.
The US military had been funding several projects
before to create autonomous land vehicles, at the point where
they already developed autonomous drones and other flying vehicles.
The first vision for AVs was the military vision.
In general, we said that robots should do the "3D" jobs, where
the three Ds stand for the qualities of the jobs that humans don't want to do--
dull, dangerous, and dirty.
And the military application is dull, dangerous, and dirty.
The DARPA challenges came at an opportune time,
in which exciting developments in various fields of science
and technology created conditions to make the goal look feasible.
For example, sensing technology like LiDAR
had improved accuracy and affordability.
That provided a way for vehicles to easily sense the world around them.
Important developments in probabilistic robotics
made AVs able to localize in an environment
and track the other vehicles.
Moreover, the increased computation available at the time
made it possible to run those algorithms in real time.
The first DARPA Challenge was a disaster,
in the sense that nobody arrived at this finish line.
However, people realized that autonomous vehicles for civilian application
would be feasible with just a bit more development.
Many of the first challenges participants
went on to found the companies that work in self-driving cars now.
The second vision was now the vision of the personal chauffeur.
Forget the military applications and the driving in some faraway desert,
we can make cars on our roads drive by themselves.
As discussed in previous videos, this is at the Level 5 vision--
a car that can drive anywhere.
People realized quickly that this is a very ambitious goal
from a technical point of view, and also the economics may not work out.
The competing vision for AVs is that of "mobility as a service".
Ridesharing services like Uber, created in 2010,
showed a different way to think about personal mobility.
If you need a car, you can call one, get on, get off with minimal friction.
Of course, there were taxis before, but they filled
a different niche, the business niche.
In many places, prices were kept high by artificially limiting the supply
by limiting number of taxi permits.
Uber showed that single cars could act as a form of public transportation.
You don't own the car, just like you don't own the buses or trains
or subway cars.
Now, it is unclear whether the economics of ridesharing services is sustainable.
Companies like Uber have been losing money for years
because they subsidize the rides to gain market share.
There's also some regulatory uncertainty.
In some parts of the world, governments have
challenged the business model of making drivers contractors
rather than employees, which allows the companies to have
relatively large margins.
Everybody's been enjoying artificially cheap rides.
In any case, ridesharing services are a great complement to public transport.
People realized that AVs could be the technology that
will make the field extremely profitable by removing
the extra cost for the driver.
It's interesting to compare the vision of Level 5 chauffeurs
to the vision of autonomous mobility on demand.
There are two aspects to understand, technology and economics.
For Level 5 cars, we need to quantify the value of autonomy for the customer.
Tesla has done the market research for us.
Tesla has been selling the option to have the car that you buy today
to be "fully self-driving" in the future.
That option cost $10,000 today.
Now, of course, today, the customer buys only a promise.
If the functionality were already there, people would pay more.
Let's double the figure and say that autonomy for a personal car
would be worth $20,000 on average to the customer.
Say that the car lasts a minimum of 10 years.
The value of autonomy is $2,000 per year.
Now let's look at the economics of taxi services.
There are many studies to discuss the price structure.
The major cost is not the car itself, it's not the fuel or maintenance,
but it's the driver's wages.
In the US, the average taxi driver makes $36,000 per year.
If autonomy can get rid of the driver, the value would be $36,000 per year.
This simple calculation shows that autonomous mobility on demand
is much more feasible economically, because the budget you
have to build a system with is almost 20 times larger than for the Level 5 vision.
From the technical perspective, autonomous mobility on demand
only requires Level 4 capabilities, because the operator
can choose where and when to deploy the taxi service.
There are also more efficiencies to be gained
when considering a company that operates a large fleet of self-driving cars used
as taxis.
The cars will be cheaper to build and more comfortable.
They might look more like living rooms on wheels
than the sedans currently used for taxes.
It is cheaper to build and maintain a fleet of cars
with high usage and turnover, perhaps being recycled every two years,
than having many personal cars that must last at least 10 years.
There's a high cost in supporting 10-years-old autonomy features.
We talked about mobility on demand for people.
The same applies to cargo.
In places like the US, most land-based goods transportation
is realized using trucks.
Autonomous trucks are an even better possible deployment
target for autonomy.
They need to work only on highways, which is a very structured environment, in which
is easier to drive than in urban environments.
In summary, in this video, we talked about the recent history of AVs,
and we discussed how the vision changed from military use to personal chauffeur
to autonomous mobility on demand.