Hi, my name is Frank.
And in this video,
we're going to take a look
at Duckietown DP twenty one Molk Robot
in here, you will see,
is a box from Duckietown that contains
all the parts necessary for the robot.
Let's take a look at what's inside.
So opening the box,
removing the protection from you'll see
your Jetson nanotube gigabit version
set aside.
You'll have your two ducks.
Obviously,
you'll have your wheels.
These are your two wheels.
You will have your motor
with the encoder assembly here.
You also have a micro SD card reader.
And inside here, under the SD protection
back, you have one of them
is the back plate.
So this goes to back off the robot
and then this is your motor driver
controller and you connect
all your accessories
like sensors onto this
board instead of the Jetson
in this bag, you have your fan
as well as your power switch.
You also have the blue part
is your camera Mount Holder.
And we also have a USB
to micro USB connector.
And inside this white box
is your camera module.
We'll take a look.
You'll see here it is your camera with
the short ribbon attached to it already
inside here.
Oops.
So this is your micro SD card
and this is your Wi-Fi adapter dongle
in here.
You will see the cables that you need
to build your Duckiebot
as well at a Internet cable.
You will also have the dot matrix
for your back of your robot for
telling the other robot where Duckiebot is
as well as you also have some stickers.
You have a screwdriver
in here.
You have a this is your front connect
the front front light this large pieces,
your front light and then
the other two included.
One is the image sensor.
And then you also have a display module.
This is your display module,
you can see a little screen over there.
This is your only display
and
it's a bit hard to take it out
inside here you can see
your Duckiebot battery.
You have all sorts of screws in here,
and then this is basically
the old white back wheel
underneath the chassis,
don't throw the box away yet.
Underneath you will
find these blue pieces.
That's your main robot chassis.
So don't panic if you don't find your
robot chassis parts.
OK, let's build this robot.
Then before we build anything,
we're going to take apart and piece out
the plastic piece we need
for building our DP.
Twenty one local robot
to open them up.
And as you can see, all the pieces
are actually on there already.
The only thing we will
need is to pop them off.
So these are already cut.
So I need to do is just very carefully
break off all the parts you will need.
And that's the first port and then
the second word contains the larger part,
where one of them is going to be the top
of the car and the one of them
is going to be part of your car.
And you also have some
bumper pieces over there.
These are your motor holder pieces.
We'll go through them later one by one
after you have broken up all the pieces.
Now you're ready to actually
build your robot.
First, we're going to install
the drive unit and install the motors.
Now, before you start,
another thing to note is that there are
protective film on these.
All the plastic pieces that you just broke
up where you can do is you can
just easily peel them off.
And you will have a relatively shiny bald
first, we're going
to install our drive base
to do that first grab two piece of metal
nut and then insert into those two grooves
next.
You want to be very careful how you
hold this board as if you did it wrong.
You will have you will have
trouble installing your OMU unit,
make sure these two screw holes is facing
you while this triangular bit is facing
forward that will ensure
you're holding it upside down.
Right.
If you flip it, you will have trouble
later installing your Ayumu unit
to install your motor,
grab these two pieces,
insert like this,
and then these will hold your motor,
make sure your motors
wire connection faces inward
like this.
These will be where you
attach your wheels later.
Next, we want to align the holes
and then putting these long screws in.
These are the longest screw
offered in the package.
Next, we want to connect the cables before
you put Pollsmoor in, there will be
a very painful process to do that.
Notice that one of the connectors are
larger, one of the connectors are smaller.
The larger one goes to the motor itself.
There's also groups on it.
So make sure you don't force
the connectors as they're pretty fragile.
You want to make sure you
align them correctly.
And it should be very easy to presetting
once you have the cables.
There's the cable management.
So right there, you want to insert
your cables through that.
Be careful very gently.
You don't want to break that little piece.
And that's one part of the motor.
And then you just do
it for the other side.
It might also be a good idea
to plug in the cables first.
Next, we're going to install the EMU,
the EMU is the board with two holes,
a connector and a bunch of
pink connectors.
You want to grab the longer cable.
Make sure when you plug in these cables,
be very gentle as there is a direction
and you don't want to bend the paint
grab to nylon screws and two nylon knots.
Where you want to do is you want to insert
your AMMU right there like this.
They should be perfectly aligned.
So if you flip the board time,
you will not stay.
Next, you want to
rulz this wire up through there.
We want to do is you want to screw
from the reverse side
and then have the nuts through there.
Make sure that you are using the nylon
screws,
since they are electronic components
on the board and you don't want
to use metal parts to short them.
Just like that, next, we want to install
our pactio assembly to do that,
still have the motor facing towards you,
and then we are going to do
is with these two screws.
They're going to start to stand off.
Like, so I recommend you read
the cables outside the stand off.
Then that will mount your motor,
need another two sets of screws.
Now you have complete
your bottom drive unit.
Next, we're going to install our battery,
hold our power to do this.
We need a battery and these four pieces
from the plastic, we have also notes
that there are plastic protection films.
Don't forget to peel them out
while you put this together.
Make sure these two school halls
are like shown in the image
not upside down, as you will
have trouble installing later.
So make sure
your left hand side should have a screw
that's closer to the edge and your right
hand side should have a screw that's
farther to the edge and your
pointing front to do that.
First you want to insert a few nuts.
These are going to be helpful for later
when you connect other parts of the robot.
Basically, if you see a shape like this,
there should be a nut inside of it.
Those are for holding the nuts
still while you're squirting.
Next, we want to preplanned some
of the schools in the board,
these will be very helpful
when we start our Jetson's panels,
so just make sure these are
all in those four holes.
As shown and then you want to do is
you want to flip it upside down.
You want to basically put some nylon,
not to hold them in place.
Just like that now you
want to flip it over.
Next, we're going to start
installing the size again.
Make sure you have a.
Basically, you have a knot in all of these
shaped grooves where these are holding
the knot, if you're having trouble putting
these together,
what the goal is, is the flat side.
So it's a hexagon shape, right?
The half of the flat side should sitting
just like that.
Next, we're going to put
this assembly together.
So where you want to do is, as you
can see, there are some notches and
little notches all over.
We want to do is you want to align them.
And what you should have is they
will just perfectly fitting
just like that, and you will
have the longer part towards you
next.
Where you want to do is you want
to grab two smaller size metal screw,
flip this upside down very carefully
without dropping ending up.
And then you can see the amazing
assembly pulling together right there.
And all of them should fit perfectly.
Just like that.
Next, we're going to just
grab these two pieces.
And then those two are going to be
the battery stopper,
so make sure your battery is actually
upside down when sliding right in there.
And also where you can see is
this little hole will be the way of you
accessing the battery
then will you want to do is just simply
insert these tubes
right there
and your battery shouldn't
move around anymore.
Next, we're going to have the exciting
part of putting the top the battery part,
as well as the drive part together.
So to do that, you simply
put it on there
and then we want to do it very carefully.
Also router cables through.
So the immutable goes through the front
big hole and then the two drivetrain cable
or the motor cable
goes on the back just like that.
Then you want to put the screws
to basically secure them together.
There should be four schools
in total that you want to put it.
And now your top part and the bottom
part are connected together.
Next, you want to do is
install your motors.
We want to grab these two
white little spacers,
then your wheels should
go right like that.
And now your Duckiebot DP twenty
one most resembles a car.
Next, we're at the exact moment of
opening the Jets and that'll
be very careful if you're
doing this in the winter.
Watch out for static chargers.
Widgets and Nano should sit
on your Duckiebot like this.
Next, we're going to install our
Jessan Nano.
I'll cover there's basically two parts.
As you can see,
they resemble a somewhat different shape.
What's that?
This part have a little loose piece on it
that basically helps you to cover
your Jetson 2G version when you put
together the sidepiece notes that you
might have to let go Jetson Nano a little
bit for the sidepiece to sit
perfectly and huggin the Jetson Nano
once you have a line down.
Skouris Grusin.
Not that there is another little piece
that if you accidentally pop it off like
me, you can just stick it back in,
that basically it was for the two
different jets and nanobots,
again, for the other side.
Same story.
Make sure they align perfectly.
Once you have make sure you adjust
and then I'll sit tight in the robot,
you can then put out your nylon screws
to make sure the detonator
doesn't move to drive.
Once you have installed your two I o plate
and the two side plates will you want
to do is you want to grab these little
spacers and then just pop
it right onto the screws.
Next, why you want to do is you want
to grab the spacers, you need two of them
double connect it like this.
And then two of them at just the regular
size, and then you want to screw them
onto the screws,
so the two long one goes in the front.
And the two short ones grossing about.
Next, you want to connect the battery
cables for the battery cables.
You'll have a total
of three battery cables,
you will have one with two and
then two regular cables.
So first, we want to do is want
to connect this to end of the cables
on the bottom USB swap,
then right into
the battery pack.
It should fit very neatly
at the correct Linus
for your middle cable,
where you want to do
is you want to root it.
Thorough
and then plug it upside down.
Just like that,
and then for your other
cable where you want to do
is you want to plug it in.
And then rode it all the way to.
Just like that, next,
we're going to plug in our Wi-Fi card,
Wi-Fi card goes to the top, you the USB
slot that's next to the HDMI cable.
Next, we're going to install
our back bumper assembly.
First, plugging the cable in for this one.
We're going to use a short cable.
Your back bumper should have the little
triangular trapezoidal tip on top.
When you connect them,
make sure your router cable through the
hole where the motor is routed to.
Should look like that
then you're just going
to screw this grusin.
Next, we're going to install
the controller,
the controller board holder,
so to install that, it's very simple.
It's just two screws.
So the controller is
going to go at the back
end.
Where we want to do is
to screws and then screw.
Uncontrollable should be standing up
a little bit behind
the regular display board.
Next, we're going to install the fan
assembly to install the fan
and just put it right there.
And then you should use
the longer of the four screws.
We can also do is you can pre table
management a little bit since we don't
meet that much of a fan table outside.
Next, we're going to grab our control
board and start installing the wires first
you want to install your friend header,
the fan header should be plugged onto
the microcontroller boards pings as
illustrated in the picture next to work.
And why are these motor cables?
So to do so we want to do is you want
to use this thought as your guide
or McKibbon management site
and then you will be able to
just like that.
Slide them writing, as well as
allowing them
onto the Jets Nanos ping header.
And then make sure you remember
which cable is which, if not,
then you can just
yank it a little bit and then you
can tell which one is from which.
Make sure your router allied cable towards
the right hand side as the LCD connector
would go to this one
might be a little bit of a stretch.
Just be very careful
not to break any connectors.
Just like that,
you do seem to connect your motor cable,
make sure so your right one goes
on to the top of the two slot.
That and your bottom line
goes to the left, Malter.
And just like that, and you can tuck away
slacks a little bit inside next,
you want to connect?
I am cable
to your connector.
That's in the middle
right there.
Just want to plug it in.
Going to be very gentle,
you don't want to break the board,
and that's who I am you going
next to, we're going to install
the camera assembly.
So first we're going to put our camera,
the ribbon cable through.
Like that
camera should have these four
little notches facing the camera
like that.
And then you want to insert.
The four smaller,
smaller sized nylon screws.
Just like that.
You want to installed the nuts,
the four extremely things,
small nylon nuts at the back.
Next, we want to do is we want to connect
this metal piece
or the connector piece actually
to the camera assembly, to do that
we want to do is see there's a little slot
right there and it should align
perfectly with the slope right there.
We want to do is for one side,
grab a middle school
pocket through.
And then connect on that at the end.
And then for the other end,
we want to do is there's a single plastic
piece standoff we want to do is
you want to grab a metal screw
and then
poke it right through
from the back to the front.
So that you can screw
this plastic piece on.
Just like that, I have one facing
front and one school facing downward.
Next, we want to do is you want
to grab another connector cable
and then we want to do is you want to flip
to the back and then
plug in to this point.
Like that,
additionally, you want to put another
cable on top right corner or
top left corner excuse me,
and you want to insert it right there
just like that,
then we're going to meet
these two piece together
going around the cable through
just like how we related to Rimu.
And then pull it through all the way.
Just like that,
and then these are going to be connecting
towards the middle one, the first one
we also wanted to tell.
So this is the one that connects
to the middle piece, this one
to be connecting to the back
of the three ports over there.
Right there.
And this one is going to connect.
To this point,
which is in the middle of the bottom three
right there.
So this one should be empty and then this
one goes to the top, her top part
of the front bumper already
and then the middle cable after
from bumper LCD shirttail
to the latter of these three.
Next, we're going to just
install this onto their.
SO to do that, we're just going
to grab some screws and a security.
Once we have put the front bumper
assembly, we're going to attach
a camera ribbon cable.
Make sure your metal part
is facing the right way.
It's always a good rule of thumb
that the metal part should be facing
the trace side
and then the plastic side should have
to prove I should have the blue side
facing from the camera ribbon cable
next to work and to install the distance
sensor module on the stand off.
That's standing up.
So the camera in the distance
module is a little piece.
We want to do is you just want to
attach it right there,
want to do is just attach it right there
and then scream your nylon that.
Next, we want to connect this assembly
to the plate where you want to do is
grab the extremely short piece of cable
and then plug it in from the bottom.
Just be again, be very
careful with the connector.
Like that, and then you want to plug in
the third quarter just right there.
Lastly, we can install the interactive
cover to do that, we're going
to first install our button.
So here's our button we want to do is you
want to unscrew and get
the nut after that.
And the next we want to do is make sure
it's facing upwards
with the Fangoria on the right hand side.
The screen on the left hand side
that you want to do is just simply.
Scoop Arcangel not.
Right, that and this will
hold the buttons stable.
Make sure you align
the button so it looks nice.
Just like that,
next, we're going to install the screen,
so to install the screen.
Simply
put, four Nilus screws and then
tie them up with a nylon, that's.
Next, we're going to connect
to the display table,
this might be a little bit tricky if you
get a cable like I do,
where it's only two black cables and one
yellow and one red cables,
if that's the case,
the black cable next to the red cable,
that should be your ground and the other
black cable next to the yellow
cable, that's your state.
So there are actual labels on the
screen itself, as well as
labels on the driver hat.
Just make sure these each wire goes
to where they intend to go and they are
properly aligned next to, well,
plugging the button and
displaying cable for the button.
There is a port on the board.
That's a stop button.
So you just connect it right there.
And then as for the display cable,
you connect it right there
and then what you do is you carefully
wrapped it up,
then attached to it
to complete the install,
put your top play along in these
four corners and the two standoffs.
And I simply use two nylon screws
and screw adding.
For the front to stand off
to other nylon, screw nylon nuts, sorry,
and then simply tighten it off.
Lastly, plugging in your power cable,
the split off power cable
show in the first port.
Plugging the other USB cable
from the power bank to the fourth port
on a controller
and plugging the USB charging port
on the power bank into the port,
that's next to the splatting USB port.