We want to create autonomous vehicles that are intelligent enough
to drive us around.
We don't see autonomy as a binary value:
either you have it, or not, but as a continuum of capabilities
that vehicles might possess.
I will present a generally accepted classification
called the "levels of automation", from Level 0
to level 5, which means completely autonomous.
Because it was created by automotive engineers,
they used the word "automation",
but roboticists like to use the word "autonomy" here.
This graphic shows the description of the levels of autonomy.
Let's start with Level 5.
Level 5 corresponds to a completely autonomous car.
These cars don't exist today.
A level 5 car is a car that you can call and will show up at your door.
It will ask you where you want to go, and it will get you there
while you relax and play Sudoku in the back.
Think of a taxi, but without a taxi driver,
and completely missing the pedals or the steering wheel.
Let's get back to Earth and see what exists today.
In Level 0 cars the human fully controls the car,
in the sense of steering and acceleration at all normal times.
There can still be some electronic mediation between the user's commands
and the car's actuators in case of emergency.
Since the 90s, there have been electronic systems such as ABS  (anti-lock braking
system) and ESC (electronic stability control)
as well as many other variations on those ideas.
You have felt them if you have ever driven on a wet surface,
on snow and ice, and something happened, and you slammed on the brakes,
and heard some weird vibrations, and eventually you came to a safe stop.
Without assistance, the car would have spun out of control.
More recently, Level 0 features include the generation of safety warnings,
such as a parking warning or a lane departure warning.
These features require the system to be aware of the environment,
so they need cameras or distance sensors.
However, the system does not act.
The warning tells the driver that something is concerning
and it is the driver that must rectify the situation.
In Level 1 cars, the human shares control of the vehicle.
The human is required to maintain eyes on the road and hands
on the steering wheel, but some control is automated.
An example is a feature like automatic cruise control, which
keeps the velocity constant or the distance to the next vehicle constant,
while the human controls the steering.
These systems can reduce driver fatigue in traffic
along stretches of highway.
Another example is a parking assistance system
in which the car steers, but the human controls the speed of the vehicle.
In Level 2 cars, the machine can take full control of the vehicle
for both steering and acceleration.
These cars already exist.
Level 2 cars can drive along a lane by themselves.
They may still require confirmation from the user in some cases, for example
when to initiate a lane change.
At Level 2 there are two "drivers", a human driver and a machine driver,
and they alternate.
The human must be alert and ready to take back control at any time.
In Level 3 cars, the human would be supposedly allowed to direct attention
away from the driving task.
In a Level 3 car you will be able to watch a movie on your phone,
but you still have to sit-in the driver's seat
and be ready to take over when the system requires you to do it.
Whether safe Level 3 systems are possible is still an open question.
The problem here is that, presumably, when
the car would ask you to take back control,
you would have to react very quickly.
And you can imagine it would take you a few seconds just
to stop watching the movie, and try to get your bearings,
and assess the situation.
Level 3 seemed a good idea at the beginning.
It seemed a small, feasible, incremental step from Level 2.
However, people have realized that it may
be more difficult to create Level to 2 than the higher levels of autonomy.
In levels 4 and 5, the car is completely autonomous.
There's only one driver, which is the machine.
You sit in the back and the car gets to the destination.
The difference between level 4 and 5 is just the scope.
Level 5 means that the car can operate anywhere, on any road,
on any condition.
So the steering wheel is completely useless.
Level 4 means that the car is able to be autonomous in only in a smaller operating domain.
Level 4 is feasible, depending on the scope.
An autonomous taxi company can choose where and when to operate.
It can choose to deploy in sunny weather rather than in  snowy weather.
There are already several examples of companies deploying an autonomous taxi
service in limited areas.
It is now a question of progressively enlarging the scope.
Level 5 is the North Star for the field.
It gives us the direction, although we may never reach it.
As of today, Level 5 autonomy does not appear
to be inconceivable, although it is hard to speculate on a timeline.
The more we understand about these problems, the more optimistic
we are about getting there eventually.
But the timeline seems to expand as we learn of the genuine challenges
that we need to solve.
To summarize, we have seen the definition of the levels of autonomy.
Although they are numbered 0 to 5, and in the past
we went incrementally from 0 to 1 to 2, there is a discontinuity at Level 3.
Most of the industry players are starting directly at Level 4,
skipping Level 3.