There are two words that you often find in the discussions
about self-driving cars: "autonomous" and "automated".
These words have different meanings depending on who uses them;
and the meanings change with time.
Sometimes they're used interchangeably;
however, they do imply something slightly different.
Let's look at the etymology.
The word "automation" comes from the Greek "automaton", which
meant something that acts by itself.
People called automata those mechanical devices
that could recreate complex motions that were mechanically stored.
There are examples of such devices created millennia ago,
but I will give you a more recent example.
100 years ago automatic pianos, or "pianolas",
were something common in the West.
The music was encoded in perforated papers that would be read mechanically.
Each hole corresponded to a key that would be pressed.
Eventually, the word "automated" was used to describe manufacturing machines that
would always repeat the same motion.
This word has a very industrial flavor to it.
The other word, "autonomous", means literally something
that has its own laws, in the sense that it is self-governing.
This suggests something that does not follow predefined steps,
but, rather, it has some internal laws or principles or goals
that it must achieve.
The actions that are chosen are those that achieve
the goals given the current scenario.
In the field of robotics, we talk about "autonomous robots".
It's actually to make the distinction with respect
to the previous generation of machines.
Another word we use is "embodied autonomy",
which clarifies that the systems we're interested in
are those that have a body.
They are em-bodied.
These are systems that interact with the real world, as opposed
to a virtual world.
What does "robot" mean?
Robot comes from the Czech word robota, which means forced labor.
Robots are machines that work for us.
I would not say they're "forced", because they
don't have any choice, or the ability to choose,
or the consciousness to understand their place in the world.
The way that robotics contributes to society
is by creating machines that can do the dull, dirty, and dangerous work
that humans should not do.
When we say robot, classically we mean both
fixed machines like industrial manipulators, as well
as those robots that move in an environment, like a vacuum cleaner,
a drone, or the micro-robots that one day will be in your guts fixing you up.
For moving robots, we use the word "vehicle", which comes from Latin.
A vehicle is something that moves and carries
something else, like people or cargo.
When regular people say "autonomous vehicles" they mean "self-driving cars".
However, for the roboticist, also a drone and a vacuum cleaner,
are autonomous vehicles.
The reality is that the concepts we're going to talk about in this course
can be applied to any autonomous vehicle, not just cars.
I presented to you the consistent nomenclature that we will follow.
We defined automation, autonomy, robot, and vehicle.
There are other words that we need to define,
such as intelligence and intelligent, but this merits a longer discussion.