This short video is an introduction to version control with git.
Why do we need to use version control?
One reason is collaboration: it allows you
to work on the same project with many other people.
With version control, you can work on parallel branches,
which means different versions of the code at the same time.
Version control is also an essential part of a formal development process.
It's fun to look at the history of version control.
In the '60s the way you would store code was just to print it out.
This is Margaret Hamilton next
to the source code for one
of the Apollo missions to the moon.
In the 90s, the main tool for Russian
control was CVS, in which each file
would have an independent history.
Subversion introduced a client-server architecture and the notion of snapshots
of the entire codebase, instead of single files.
A big improvement came with distributed version control system, such as Git,
which is now the most used system, and the one we are going to use.
On top of Git there is a large ecosystem
of services such as GitHub and Gitlab. such as Github and Gitlab. These services provide features
like issue tracking and pull requests that make collaboration easy.
Git was created by Linus Torvalds, the same Finnish guy who invented Linux.
And as he says, just like Linux, Git was named after him.
Git was created for the Linux development.
There was no other tool that was sufficient for projects of that scale.
You can find on Github a copy of the repository for the Linux kernel,
and you will see that it has millions of
commits and thousands of contributors.
Linus inventing Git is a demonstration
of the principle that Jedi knights
build their own lightsabers.
This principle also works for robotics.
As a roboticist, we will use plenty of tools,
but chances are that, none is quite sufficient.
And you will need to go and extend
them or build your own.
Getting back to Git: At the core of Git there is
the concept of a commit graph.
For example, this is the commit graph
for one of the Duckietown repositories.
On Github you access this through the "insights"
menu and then choosing "network".
This is a graph where each node
represents a state of the source code.
The edges are changes that bring
you from one state to another.
The graph is not linear,
There can be parallel branches
in which development happens,
for example,
two people can work at the same time
in the same project without
interfering with each other.
Then, later, they can merge their work.
This is another example of a commit graph.
In this visualization, time goes
from the bottom to the top.
This is the first repository for the Duckietown project in 2016.
You can see that at the beginning only few people were working on the project.
Then, eventually, many other people joined.
And so the graph became less linear.
If we zoom in at the top,
you will see the "master" branch
This contains the master copy of the project, .
In the sense that eventually all of the
branches will be merged into master.
If we zoom in, we see that at the time
that this snapshot was taken,
there were many branches that awaited to be merged in the masterbrand.
Git is incredibly flexible.
It doesn't specify the semantics
for the different branches,
but there are conventions that are
very useful to organize development.
One of the most used is the "Git Flow"
model, which specifies how teams can
coordinate the development
of different versions in parallel.
We provide you with several pointers to
resources that you can use
to learn Git.
In your journey, you will realize that it is very
powerful and it has many features.
Don't be intimidated.
Keep in mind that you typically only
need the basic functionality of Git.
This is a summary of the basic
operations that you might want to learn.
You should learn how to clone a repository,
how to commit modifications, and how to push the changes remotely.
Branching and merging are very
useful to learn at some point.
Finally, it is very useful to learn GitHub
features such as pull
requests and issue tracking.